Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/manojpyla (LinkedIn) github.com/manojpyla (Other)

Top Skills

R

Python (Programming Language)
Machine Learning

Languages

English

Hindi

Telugu

Certifications

Intermediate R
Join Data in SQL
Introduction to Python
Intermediate Python
Introduction to Shell

Honors-Awards

Nucleite Of The Month
Nucleite Of The Month August- 2015
Team Award

Manoj Pyla

Data Scientist | MS in Business Analytics (STEM), Class of 2020 | University of California Irvine

Irvine, California

Summary

Data Science professional with over 5 years of experience working with a large volume of data and statistically leveraging it to acquire business insights and preemptively drive the business goals towards the organization's mission. In the past engaged with Commercial Lending, Retail lending, and Healthcare clients to help them explore the data to Detect Anomalies, Perform Descriptive Analysis, Develop Predictive models, and Prescriptive models. Have a unique blend of Data Science, Statistics and rich Software engineering experience.

KEY STRENGTHS

- Identify the objective of complex data problems and work with complex datasets leveraging the relevant tools.
- -Translate and communicate insights as tangible and actionable recommendations.
- Collaborate with multiple stakeholders to conduct end-to-end analysis.

SKILLS

- -Algorithms: Linear and Logistic Regression, K-NN, Clustering, Random Forest, Decision Tree, Support Vector Machine (SVM), Principal Component Analysis (PCA), XGBoost
- -Technical: Python (NumPy, Pandas), Data mining, C++, R, SQL, PL SQL, Weka, Tableau, SAS, Hadoop, Spark, Pig, Hive, Statistics, Tensorflow, Keras, Artificial Neural Networks, CNNs, NLTK, Sci-kit Learn
- Statistics: T-test, Hypothesis Testing, ANOVA

Experience

DXC Technology SVC INFO DEVELOPER December 2015 - July 2019 (3 years 8 months) Bengaluru Area, India

- Increased revenue capability by 50–70% through operational data source architecture redesign. Project completed on time while maintaining 100% operational capacity.
- Reduced downtime to 20 from 36 hours, and gained 40% performance by implementing an automation framework for the product deployment process.
- Spearheaded the data clean-up efforts, ultimately leading to the tens of thousands of quality data records for report analysis service, improving productivity by 34% of recovery and acquisition business strategy.
- Improved service request resolution time to an average of 45 minutes maximum from approximately 150 minutes.
- Achieved multimillion-dollar cost savings and Led a team of 9 reporting analysts on a commercial information strategy project to realize a 32 percent performance efficiency increase.
- Provided Product Module-Management and team-leadership contributing to the successful completion of many full life-cycle projects within aggressive time frames.
- Organized various multi-vendor meetings to discuss and implement an optimal solution for various challenges and business problems faced during the project lifecycle.

Nucleus Software Exports Limited Software Development Engineer December 2013 - December 2015 (2 years 1 month)

- Built audit reports identifying issues in payment module thereby reducing product errors by 80%. These reports were later adopted for all modules within the finance product.
- Brought on board to lead the data warehouse and report analysis for profitable growth. Vigorously pursued a strategic partnership to build an efficient decision support analysis product for executives.
- Managed three major projects aggregating \$15 million- Loan management product, banking data warehouse, and product architecture upgrade.
- Developed interactive reports and dashboards to understand product performance over time with an increase in the volume of data.
- Coordinated multi-cultural teams across various locations, and liaison with the collection and recovery teams of 11 countries and the strategy executives on defining the future business goals.

Education

University of California, Irvine - The Paul Merage School of Business Master of Science, Business Analytics(STEM) · (2019 - 2020)

Professor Ram Meghe Institute of technology and Research, badnera

Bachelor of Engineering (B.E.), Computer Science and Engineering · (2008 - 2013)

Ira International School

Junior College +2, Mathematics and Computer Science · (2006 - 2008)